the following is a production of Frank
de Freitas and the internet resume of
holography
[Music]
we have to fight after annihilate kill
kill kill hell
hello this is Frankie Freitas and
welcome to holotalk the internet's laser
and holography talk show our toll-free
number is
1-800-458-3525 or you can send an email
to holotalk
poloworld.com we've got telephone calls
we've got emails we've got special
guests coming up so thank you for tuning
in and let's get this week's show on the
road
hello everybody and welcome to another
week of Holo talk I'm sorry we had to go
through a couple weeks of repeats uh the
first week actually we were I was
actually trying to contact Jim Wilford
down in Panama and I continuously got
the international operator that said no
no lines were available so uh we're
still going to work with getting Jimmy
on the show and we're probably going to
do an interview with him late at night
when there are more phone lines open
into Panama from the United States
uh last week I had some surgery done and
just couldn't get a chance to uh
have the show done so uh
we're back here this week in full swing
thank you very much I I did get a few
emails from you and it meant quite a bit
to me getting email s
saying that you hope everything was okay
I had a tumor removed and so far so good
everything looks okay so we're back in
the swing of things here with holotalk
this week guest is Alan Rhodey from Ross
books and Ross books of course as you
may already know is the publisher of the
world famous holography handbook which
got so many holographers started in the
field to begin with including myself
back in 1983 when I got my own Studio
together and also the holography
marketplace which is a reference book
for people who are looking for companies
to do business with in the field of
holography so both of these things are
very driving forces in the field of
holography and they've all come out of
the Publishing House of Ross books
what's going to be interesting about
this interview is Alan's going to tell
us about a very uh incredible
portable holographic camera that zone
has just developed so I'm not going to
go into any details with any explanation
here I'll let Alan do that when he comes
on in a few moments
uh just to let you know every other week
we're going to do our listeners call-ins
and also their email so if you have any
questions about the fields of lasers and
holography you can send them through uh
toll-free you can call on the phone
1-800-458-3525
or you can send an email to holotalk
homerworld.com and I'll just go through
reference materials and see if I can't
get the answer to your questions and uh
if you happen to call in we'll use your
voice on the air and if you happen to
write the email and more than happy to
read your email
during the show so let's move on I just
saw a a study that showed that the
average listening time to a real audio
presentation this was done by real
networks is four minutes four minutes is
the average listening time to any audio
presentation on the web so we're going
to try and cut back the show a little
bit sometimes we're 40 minutes long
sometimes we're 30 minutes long but we
realize that not everyone has a lot of
time to sit and listen at their
computers to the show so we're going to
just try and keep it the pertinent
shows and cut out some of the uh the
Chit Chat and this and that and try and
get the show times down a little bit
that they're a little bit more
manageable manageable both for us to
produce them and also for you to listen
to without taking out any of the
exciting content or what many of you
feel that you've said that it's exciting
content anyway I don't want to start
bragging about my own show here so let's
move on to the interview with Alan rodey
who's very interesting it was nice
talking to him he's going away on
vacation to Hawaii so we want to wish
him a a real happy vacation there's
nothing like getting away from it all
that for a week or two just to clear the
head out and get the cobwebs out of the
head so Alan you have a good time in
Hawaii if you get a chance to log on and
you're listening to the show I hope
everything's going well so let's move on
this is our interview with Alan Rhody
from Ross books
yes it's Alan Rudy there Alan this is
Frankie Freitas hey Frank how are you
okay how you doing I'm fine thanks could
you tell us a little bit about what your
company's doing I know you have the
holography handbook sure well I wanted
to uh you know I just Zapped you an
email just remember you said is there
any questions you might want to ask yeah
um I just came back from FBI and I just
wrote this big article on the the Sony
thing on the new portable uh instant
portrait system oh it's incredible yeah
yeah that was pretty cool now this this
is being manufactured by Sony right
what's what's a little a little bit of
the news on that
okay are we are we live I'm recording it
yeah oh okay hold on there I gotta get a
sip of coffee here okay go ahead I have
some ice cream here you sip some coffee
I'll sip some iced tea this is informal
uh basically Sony just unveiled the
first uh fully portable
portrait hard ethics diagram portrait
printing system by portable our idea of
portable sometimes means like a Walkman
right and it is something like that no
kidding can be used Outdoors it's uh
basically uh you sit in front of a
scanning digital camera that's on a rail
and the rail's about three four feet
long the camera travels down the rail it
takes
225 separate images
that it feeds into an image Processing
Unit you know just through a wire okay
and the image processing unit is located
in a box about the size of the desktop
copying machine wow it goes through the
image processor the image processor
takes all the different Parallax views
and regenerates
295 different views left to right
sends them into
an Optics board located on a little
isolation platform built into this thing
get out and the uh the condensed images
are well actually the images are shown
on a an LCD screen it's a spatial light
modulator valve they call it and it
condensed into a vertical strip onto a
diffusion diffuser screen
and then it's recorded with a little
green laser a solid state laser directly
on a piece of DuPont photopolymer it
takes each exposure is a quarter second
and each exposure cycle is
um a half a second I believe and it
takes an exposure they invented a new
type of film transport mechanism kind of
based on a vcr and a Walkman I mean Sony
knows how to do that thing and the old
system of just like sandwiching a piece
of film between two pieces of glass or
whatnot it just there's too many
stability problems and they couldn't go
fast enough so they invented a pinch
roller thing similar to the inside it
reminds me of a Walkman by the diagram
where the the film is kind of looped
around and it presses up against the
exposure fast enough against the
aperture fast enough for a quick
exposure and nothing moves goes and does
you know 295 of these little vertical
slits it takes 147 seconds so a little
over two minutes the film traveled
automatically into
um under a UV lamp to cure and a little
baking chamber and now pop a piece of
plastic within three minutes with a a
stereogram hologram on photopolymer
about three inches by two inches at the
moment and it's got about four
horizontal Parallax and it can capture a
couple seconds of animation and we saw
one of the guys you know he sneezed as
you walked by yeah so a couple seconds
of Animation there and they say well
once they get more uh colored diode
lasers in there because they wanted to
operate off household current they can
make full color ones with the um
on you know panchromatic film and the
film can be loaded into a cartridge so
basically it's intended for an office
worker
Sony actually says you know we're really
not interested in holographic portraits
but once you can see they think
stereograms are the best way to present
3D digital information that's the bottom
line so the the fact that it has the
camera in it you're taking portraits
it's almost incidental to them they want
to make a a hard copy
3D output device they call their Holo
printer because it's based around the
old integral I don't know it goes back
to the early San Francisco days
apparently yeah yeah Whoever thought
it's kind of a variation on that and you
know it's got Sony's name on it now they
previewed at the spie show
they previewed the Holograms they didn't
bring the machine in but they had full
schematics and photos of the thing and
it's about the size of a uh a desktop
copy or a big um
scanner a printer yeah so it's fully
into and it's light tight and it has
internal isolation on the Optics so you
can pick the thing up and put it
wherever you want
did they give any range a price on this
no right now it's all r d what's your
guess what do you think something like
this looks interesting five figures or
six figures
it didn't seem like you know everything
was off the shelf components so it
didn't seem like it was so esoteric
they're just the first ones to really do
it all together component yeah and
upgrade it and put it all in one box and
they can afford I would assume that
laser in there is probably you know a
new fifty thousand dollars but Tony you
know they probably have pool with the
laser company
um it's basically I think that is the
main expense once you have a film
transport mechanism that's you know kind
of just that's what they've got to
specialize in it didn't seem anything
more complex than you know a VCR
certainly yeah incredible and uh you
know if if the digital input is
formatted correctly you know through
their processor uh which is you know
proprietary
um it's got I think he said 256 Megs of
ram in there and uh
you know that's kind of the heart of the
machine everything else they said well
we can make bigger Holograms if we have
bigger Optics the film's already in 12
inch wide widths so you know they can
feed it through it's just a matter of
engineering at that point
you're doing a story for a publication
I'm actually doing it for a um a web uh
a web page and they'll try to Market it
to you know any magazine that I can I
just want to let our viewers know that
uh while you're listening to the show
you can go to the Ross webpage itself
you want to tell them how they can find
it what is it www dot rossbook
rossbooks.com and I'll have a link on
the page and you can exit the real audio
player just by clicking on the browser
and bringing it to the front you don't
have to sit there staring at the screen
while the show's playing you can visit
Ross books right on the web while you're
listening to the show
now I lied doing about two hours ago so
I didn't get the email I'm sorry about
that but whatever you want to cover we
can cover great what was what was some
of the other things you had in your
email well we talked um uh of the new
emulsions the the new silver halide
emulsions now that obviously Act was not
in the game other people have to take up
the slack and some of the holographers
have been experimenting with the
different emulsions now for about six
months so we're starting to see some of
the results some nice results we saw
some very nice results with the German
emulsions HRT very high contrast give
you some really nice blacks in the
background if it's processed properly
it's a little slow but people are doing
things to speed it up a little bit so
reflection holography these were
reflection holes reflection hologram
chapters silver halide emulsions that
are kind of hard to get for your average
high school teacher now or yeah
it's really a shame that you know the
younger kids that's the Next Generation
has to come up with this field you know
correct and then there's just uh there's
a few Distributors that are still
carrying the old access stocks their
book the logography handbook is built
around the actual emulsions so we're
basically you know gathering information
for all these people and letting them
know where they can buy the stuff uh
slavich the Russian manufacturer is
bringing out some very nice emulsions
very high quality emulsions people
getting very good results on that the
Chinese are starting to develop their
own emulsions a company called hold door
they have some U.S distribution we're
getting preliminary results back on that
um
is developing some Emulsion suitable for
industrial use and
we're looking forward to
checking all these out and doing some
comparisons
what version is the holography handbook
in now uh the handbook we've just
revised with some less toxic chemistries
that was about two years ago and now
we're revising it again to you know
reflect the situation with the new
emulsions
you know that book got me uh got me on
the road with holography same with
everybody in 1983. yeah yeah I still
have that book and I really need to take
a Polaroid photo of this book so that
you could see the condition that it's in
and I mean it is just totally ripped
apart fantastic which is a good sign
that's a good sign because that means
that book's been used we get the
dog-eared copies every once in a while I
have to I have to show you this book
this has got to be the best one yet we
still sell it all over the world we're
actually uh we were talking to somebody
about a Chinese translation replay uh
because it still seems to be one of the
the you know lab manuals that you can
take in there and do a step by step
well the only thing I could do before
the holography handbook came out was
just follow the holography because I
started following it when the Museum of
Photography opens in New York but I
couldn't do any Holograms but then I
caught on to the holography handbook and
brought a copy of that home and I would
say within maybe about 10 days after
getting that book I had my first
hologram made that quick you know
back in my younger days
and we're also we're getting ready to
put out the seventh edition of the
holography marketplace that's the newest
it's a great resource yeah that's 22
Holograms in it this year
240 Pages we've got nine chapters of
really nice information informative
stuff and 900 or so listings in the
international database of holography
related businesses that's worth its
price just for the Holograms that are in
there a big 22.95 yeah you couldn't buy
all those Holograms that are in that
book especially nice ones on the cover
this year we're doing the photopolymer
it's a computer generated image and it
was produced by Crystal holographics on
DuPont's photopolymer it's fairly big
it's a nice one
um we have some dot matrix Holograms in
the book there's some 2DS there's some
2D 3DS there's 3DS there's photopolymer
embossed so it's a good represent a good
sample kit you know good representation
of what's out there today
you did a nice computer generated piece
on the fifth yeah that was interesting
uh full Parallax yeah even Sony hasn't
done a full Parallax hologram yet yeah
uh they're still doing horizontal
Parallax and the idea itself is rather
simple the engineering is a little tough
but we had Bobcats an expert holographer
work on that and Chuck hasson develop a
full Parallax printer and I'd love to
see you that you know done commercially
because they've got a good um good
response from the readers
so what's your next direction for Ross
books well we're the holography
marketplace became an annual and uh we'd
love to put out a quarterly at some
point we're very heavy into uh spreading
information over the Internet
um we get worldwide inquiries about
philography nearly every day and we
we're basically book publishers so we
like to sell books
um I'm also writing articles for
whoever's interested on the latest and
greatest telegraphy information and
we're going to just keep plugging away
we're starting to expand our circulation
uh
book clubs are starting to carry our
book to get it out there we're going to
a lot of conventions to get into the
users and potential users hands at
agencies Venture capitalists technology
companies
advertising agencies and just uh promote
the whole holography industry that's
their job
[Music]
we try
you're the
behind the motion of the field if we try
you know I had your I had your first
edition of the holography marketplace
and I can't find them anymore just
because that's worth upwards of five
hundred dollars no kidding I know it's
around I've got everything going back
over the years I know it's here some
but I cannot find it you know just as
kind of a joke because we were getting
down to the last couple dozen and we
said well we're not gonna let's put a
hundred dollar price tag on them well
book collectors found out about it these
are people outside the holography
industry because it has collectible
Holograms in there that'll never be
reprinted the book is considered rare
and collectible uh the we start getting
orders at a hundred dollars a piece that
we're even contemplating doing a buyback
at like 75.
so uh keep those old issues the
photography Marketplace and put them
away so we can all put the kids through
college
I've got one in there now
okay well what what else would you like
to say before we wrap it up uh I just
want to thank you for all your efforts
Through The Years you're holding down
the East Coast we're trying to hold down
the West Coast in the Pacific Rim so if
we all keep plugging away we'll all have
jobs that we enjoy I'm gonna stop
sending that rain this way though yeah
yeah I shouldn't say that to anyone on
the west coast like I realize you're all
going through some pretty hard times out
there with this weather
well that's why I looked on the map and
found out where there was a drought
believe it or not it's Honolulu so I'm
Hawaii bound okay well you have a good
time on vacation it was good talking to
you Alan and folks don't forget go over
there and check out that Ross books
website it's
www.rossbooks.com and just click on the
link that's on talk page and that'll
take you right over there thank you Alan
very much okay talk to you later okay
bye-bye
initiating shutdown